<Document>
  # Important Character Creation Tips
  This guide covers the parts of character creation that affect gameplay in this gamemode.
  (Cosmetic changes are unchanged and are not included here.)

  -------------------------------------------------------------

  ## Spawn Priority
  Spawn options determine where you appear **when joining an ongoing round**.

  - **Cryosleep**: You awaken inside the station’s cryosleep chamber.
  - **None**: Automatically selects whichever spawn option is valid for the map.

  The **Arrivals shuttle system does not exist** in this gamemode, so only station-based spawns are used.
  This setting is mostly preference and can safely be left on “None.”

  -------------------------------------------------------------

  ## Jobs
  In the lobby you may set job preferences. These determine which roles the system considers you for when the round begins.

  Priority works as follows:
  - High priority jobs are rolled first
  - Then medium priority
  - Then low priority

  If you are not selected for any preferred role, you may choose to:
  - Spawn as a passenger
  - Or return to the lobby to wait for the next round

  Some jobs remain locked until you gain enough playtime in accessible entry-level roles.

  [textlink="Learn more about jobs here." link="Jobs"]

  -------------------------------------------------------------

  ## Job Loadouts
  Each job allows you to select a **loadout** of clothing or minor equipment.
  Loadout items may affect gameplay:

  - Some clothing provides **armor protection**
  - Some items may **slow your movement speed**
  - Higher-responsibility roles (Engineering, Cargo, Medical, etc.) may feel these effects more strongly

  You can also select your **bag type**:
  - [color=#a4885c]Backpacks[/color]: Medium capacity, easier to store large items
  - [color=#a4885c]Satchels[/color]: Highest total storage, worst for carrying large items
  - [color=#a4885c]Duffel Bags[/color]: Largest capacity but incur a movement penalty

  -------------------------------------------------------------

  ## Traits

  ### Speech Traits
  These modify how your text appears in chat. Some are mild, while others drastically change speech patterns.

  Options include:
  - Accentless
  - Social anxiety (stutter)
  - Southern drawl
  - Pirate accent
  - Cowboy accent
  - Italian accent
  - Frontal lisp
  - Pathological liar

  It is recommended to master normal communication or mild accents before selecting strong or comedic accents.

  ### Disability Traits
  These introduce gameplay challenges. Beginners should avoid them until familiar with the game loop and station environment.

  - Blindness
  - Muted (cannot speak; use emotes or pen-and-paper)
  - Short-sighted
  - Narcolepsy
  - Pacifist
  - Paracusia (auditory hallucinations)
  - Lightweight drunk
  - Snoring
  - Unrevivable (cannot be resuscitated)

  Choose these only if you understand the difficulty they add to your play experience.

</Document>
