<Document>
  # Role Types (WIP)
  Role types define how players are expected to behave within a round of Prospect Sector. They are not “good vs. evil” designations, but mechanical responsibility tags that clarify expectations, freedoms, and boundaries. The game is cooperative by design, solo-friendly, and progression-driven, so these categories exist to reduce confusion and grief, and to help players understand what they should or should not do.


  ## Core crew roles
  Core Crew Roles are the standard round-to-round jobs. They include roles like Engineer, Cargo Tech, Botanist, Chef, Chaplain, Scientist, Medic, and Command positions such as QM and HoP.

  Expectations:
  Work toward overall station progression and survivability.
  Maintain or improve the station, produce goods, support expeditions, or run expeditions depending on your assignment.
  Follow general rules and station RP expectations.
  May participate in expeditions unless their job is explicitly needed on station (engineering upkeep, atmos stability, etc.).

  Core Crew roles are not “good guys,” but they default to cooperative play. Their actions should move the station toward higher expedition levels, better infrastructure, and better payout.


  ## Station Support Specialists
  These are roles whose mechanical purpose is to enhance station-side progression. They typically do not need to enter expeditions at all, though they may if the situation allows.

  Examples:
  Engineer, Atmos Tech, Cargo Tech, Quartermaster, Science Staff, Chef, Botanist, Musician, Chaplain.

  Expectations:
  Maintain vital systems such as power, atmos, construction, and production lines.
  Provide consumables, upgrades, gear enhancement, food buffs, materials, and research that improve the expedition team.
  React to station events (meteors, damage, fires, power outages).
  Their absence can visibly weaken the station’s ability to progress.

  These roles have high responsibility, but not increased authority. They simply matter mechanically.


  ## Expedition Roles
  These roles are built primarily for expedition gameplay and are expected to leave the station regularly.

  Examples:
  Miner, Salvager, Explorer, Security-adjacent expedition combat roles (if added later).

  Expectations:
  Participate in expeditions, obtain loot, secure materials, and increase the global difficulty unlocks.
  Understand expedition tiering and survivability.
  Cooperate with the station team by returning loot to cargo storage and distributing gear fairly.

  Expeditions are capped at short sessions (up to ~15 minutes), so they may rotate between station duties and expeds.
  Expedition roles progress the run by unlocking stronger drops and expanding the station’s capabilities.


  ## Command Roles
  Command Roles guide the flow of the round, but do not have unchecked authority.

  Examples:
  Head of Personnel, Quartermaster, Captain.

  Expectations:
  Coordinate departments, set bounties, and decide priorities for expansion, repairs, and materials.
  Manage the bounty pool responsibly (not for personal enrichment).
  Practice leadership rather than micromanagement.
  Provide clear directives for crews rebuilding the station.

  Command roles exist to enable the station, not dominate it.


  ## Free-Roam / Utility Roles
  These roles have no single required gameplay loop and can freely shift between station work and expeditions.

  Examples:
  Assistant, Maintenance Worker, Hobbyist roles (Clown, Mime, Musician).

  Expectations:
  May contribute anywhere: hauling, small repairs, minor production, or joining expeditions.
  Should not obstruct core station functions (e.g., blocking engineering).
  Not required to specialize, but expected to participate meaningfully in some form.

  Utility roles are great for new players, solo players, or people who want variety.


  ## Bound Roles
  Bound Roles are mechanically restricted by a system or another player and cannot freely deviate from it.

  Examples:
  AI-equivalent roles (Silicon) if added: must obey their lawset.
  Familiars or bonded companions (if implemented): must obey their designated player.

  Expectations:
  Follow their binding without exception unless it breaks core game rules.
  Cannot ignore their constraints for personal convenience.

  These roles exist to create unique playstyles, not power imbalance.


  ## Disruptive Roles (Scripted, Not Player-Assigned)
  Prospect Sector does not use traitors, grief roles, or antagonist slots. Any hostile force comes from:

  environmental events,
  AI malfunctions (if coded as an NPC effect),
  hostile fauna in expeditions,
  random damage to the derelict station.

  Players are never assigned a role whose purpose is to destroy gameplay for others.

  ## Solo Mode Roles
  When playing without other players, any role becomes effectively “Solo Mode.”

  Expectations:
  No RP or mechanical restrictions apply—solo players may access any system since they must progress alone.

  All job roles are purely functional in this mode.

  This ensures the game remains fully playable even with only one person online.


</Document>
