<Document>
  # Station Conduct Guidelines
  Prospect Sector does **not** use Space Law, Security forces, brig systems, nor punitive crime codes.
  Instead, the station runs on **cooperative conduct**, **leadership guidance**, and **roleplay-driven conflict resolution**.

  These guidelines explain how the crew should safely handle disputes, detainment, dangerous equipment, and emergencies in a game mode with **no antagonists** and **no police structure**.

  These guidelines are **not server rules**, but some rules reference proper station conduct and require Command and crew to behave within these expectations.

  [color=#a4885c]## General Philosophy[/color]
  - The station is a **civilian, cooperative environment**.
  - There is no police force and no “criminal code.”
  - Conflicts are resolved through RP and escalation rules.
  - Restraint is rare and only for **immediate threats**.
  - Hostile NPC fauna and environmental hazards—not players—are the true dangers.

  [color=#a4885c]## Temporary Restraint & Containment[/color]
  Crew may temporarily restrain someone **only** when:
  - A player is actively attacking others
  - A player is creating immediate, serious risk to infrastructure
  - Someone is violently escalating without RP justification
  - A character is mentally unstable (RP) and must be contained for safety

  Guidelines:
  - Use the **minimum necessary restraint**.
  - Remove restraints once the situation is safe.
  - Provide medical attention if needed.
  - Long-term confinement **does not exist** IC in Prospect Sector.

  [color=#a4885c]## Treatment of Restrained Crew[/color]
  Anyone temporarily detained retains basic rights:
  - Access to medical care
  - Access to communication unless abused
  - Retention of gear unless it is dangerous
  - Safe, non-isolated holding spaces (an office or med room)

  If the area becomes unsafe, relocate the person to a secure but humane space.

  [color=#a4885c]## Searches[/color]
  Searches may occur **only with a clear IC reason**, such as:
  - Suspected dangerous equipment in a civilian area
  - Erratic or hazardous behavior
  - Someone refusing to store expedition weapons outside the Terradrop zone

  Guidelines:
  - Searches require **reasonable cause**.
  - Only dangerous or misused items may be confiscated.
  - All harmless items must be returned.
  - Crew may refuse a search in normal areas unless they pose active danger.

  [color=#a4885c]## Dangerous Equipment Control[/color]
  - Expedition weapons, tools, and armor may be openly carried **only near the Terradrop** and expedition prep areas.
  - Elsewhere on the station, all dangerous gear must be **stored** (backpack, locker, personal storage).
  - Open-carry outside the expedition zone is prohibited unless responding to an **active emergency**.

  If someone refuses to store dangerous items and becomes a hazard, temporary containment or item confiscation is valid RP.

  [color=#a4885c]## Implants & Medical Procedures[/color]
  Prospect Sector has **no punitive implant system**.
  All implantation must follow these rules:
  - Only medical or research implants may be used
  - No forced implants without OOC consent
  - No mindshields, trackers, or “law enforcement” implants
  - Extraction or implantation is never used as punishment

  [color=#a4885c]## Punishments & Consequences[/color]
  There are **no brig sentences**, **no timers**, and **no executions** IC.

  Allowed consequences:
  - [color=#a4885c]Warning:[/color] Clear RP instructions to stop harmful behavior
  - [color=#a4885c]Confiscation:[/color] Temporarily removing dangerous or misused items
  - [color=#a4885c]Demotion:[/color] Removing a role or access if job gear is misused
  - [color=#a4885c]Relocation:[/color] Moving someone to a safe space to cool down

  Demotions require:
  - Command (Station Lead or department head) approval
  - Clear IC justification
  - Proper RP communication

  [color=#a4885c]## Handling Severe Disruption[/color]
  When a player repeatedly disrupts station operations:
  - Command should intervene via conversation or demotion
  - Crew may restrain temporarily
  - If behavior continues, contact admins via ahelp

  Long-term confinement is **not** a valid IC solution.

  [color=#a4885c]## No Major Punishments[/color]
  - No executions
  - No permanent confinement
  - No forced exile
  - These exist **only as admin OOC actions**, never IC procedures

  [color=#a4885c]## No Crime Listing[/color]
  Because there is no law system or security structure, there is **no crime list**.
  The only expectations are:
  - Cooperate
  - Maintain the station
  - Protect progression
  - Keep the environment safe and roleplay-appropriate

</Document>
