<Document>
  # Roleplay Rule 11 – Follow Reasonable Escalation

  Prospect Sector is a **cooperative progression game**, not a PvP environment.
  Conflicts may happen through RP, but escalation must always be **proportional, justified, and controlled**.

  All conflicts should begin at the **lowest appropriate level** and escalate only if the other party escalates first.
  You may match their level of escalation, but you should not jump ahead without cause.

  Escalation steps:
  - Verbal
  - Non-harmful
  - Non-lethal
  - Lethal
  - Permanently lethal (almost never justified)

  Players who genuinely attempt to de-escalate will be given more leniency.
  Someone observing you over multiple rounds should not feel like your character constantly seeks escalation.

  ## Additional Guidelines
  - Indirect escalation (such as stealing an ID that traps someone) counts as escalation.
  - Conflicts rarely justify lethal force, and **almost never** justify permanently lethal actions.
  - If someone enters crit or dies, you should take them for medical care unless there is clear IC justification not to. Doing so de-escalates the conflict.
  - You may not escalate based on unreasonable assumptions or flimsy justification.
  - Hostile mobs, dangerous anomalies, and similar non-player threats are exempt—but **you** are still responsible if you break rules attacking them or using them as tools.

  ## MRP Amendment
  Escalation rules apply even when the opposing entity is a non-player, unless clearly designated by admins.

  ## Examples of Conflict Types
  See [textlink="Examples of Conflict Types" link="RuleR11-2"].

  ## Escalation Involving Animals
  See [textlink="Escalation Involving Animals" link="RuleR11-1"].

  ## Example Scenarios
  These examples assume normal cooperative gameplay.

  ### Acceptable:
  - Someone punches you; you punch back until they stop, then bring them to medbay.
  - A clown pies you and steals your shoes; you slip them and take their mask in return.
  - You use a non-lethal tool to stop someone fleeing during an RP confrontation.
  - You stop an unauthorized person from entering a hazardous area through reasonable force.
  - Two players escalate a dispute over time into a fistfight through proper escalation.
  - Destroying a body only when an examine message indicates recovery is impossible.

  ### Prohibited:
  - Someone punches you once; you gib them.
  - Responding to a prank or annoyance (pie, shove, insult) with stabbing or lethal force.
  - Using lethal weapons to stop someone fleeing a conversation.
  - Attacking someone for entering a low-risk area without escalation.
  - Harassing a department repeatedly (breaking glasses, furniture, tools).
  - Escalating based on bad assumptions (thinking someone is trespassing when they aren’t).
  - Hiding or spacing bodies over minor disputes.
  - Stealing IDs from disconnected players.
  - Immediately restarting a lethal conflict after the other party brought you to medbay.

</Document>
