<Document>
  # Roleplay Rule 11-1 – Escalation Involving Animals

  Prospect Sector is a cooperative environment.
  Animals (pets, critters, mobs) should be treated with **basic RP respect**, but escalation rules are **looser than with players**.

  ## General Guidelines
  - **Non-pet animals** (mice, monkeys, pests) may be removed for practical IC reasons such as food, sanitation, or safety.
  - **Pets** (Ian, Renault, Remilia, Hamlet, etc.) require **escalation** before being harmed. They are unique, limited roles and should be treated similarly to crew.
  - Trapping an animal permanently is treated the same as killing it—only do so with valid IC justification.
  - Animals can escalate more quickly than players due to limited health and limited access to healing.
  - Neither side is obligated to provide medical attention to the other, but **killing someone in crit is a major escalation step** and must be justified.
  - Sensible, non-targeted mousetraps or pest-control tools do **not** require escalation.

  ## Pet Connections & Retaliation
  - Crew generally have an IC connection to **station pets** and may escalate proportionally if a pet is harmed.
  - Connections must be roleplayed—not declared.
  Example: carrying a mouse around and caring for it establishes a bond.
  - Hostile mobs (carp, bears, etc.) cannot be “adopted” for escalation purposes.

  ## Examples

  ### Acceptable:
  - A chef kills mice entering the kitchen.
  - A janitor removes pest mice roaming the station.
  - A crewmember retaliates when someone kills the mouse they’ve been carrying and caring for.
  - A pet defends itself and escalates naturally during a scuffle.
  - A crewmember stops someone attacking Ian and subdues the attacker.

  ### Prohibited:
  - Harming or trapping pets without escalation or IC cause.
  - Using harmful tools (like armed mousetraps) on pets for no reason.
  - Having a pet attack random crew without RP justification.
  - Escalating against crew because they defended themselves from a hostile mob.
  - Treating hostile wildlife as “pets” to justify escalation.

</Document>
