<Document>
  # Roleplay Rules

  These rules apply **only during an active round**.
  A round ends when the **round summary appears**. Roleplay rules remain in full effect until that moment, including while the arrivals shuttle is in transit or players are returning to cryo.

  Prospect Sector is a **cooperative, progression-based** game mode. These rules ensure that players contribute to station development, expeditions, and a healthy RP environment.

  Test modes (such as deathmatch, sandbox, mapping tests, or admin-announced experimental modes) may be exempt from Roleplay Rules.
  Players who ignore these rules are responsible for confirming that an exempt mode is active.

  Roleplay rules **do not apply to ghosts/observers** while they remain ghosts.
  Dead chat is considered an **in-game out-of-character** channel.

  See the list of [textlink="role types" link="RoleTypes"] for more information about cooperative role expectations.

  - [textlink="1. Silicons must follow Silicon Rules" link="RuleR1"]
  - [textlink="2. Familiars and bound roles must obey their designated master" link="RuleR2"]
  - [textlink="3. Roleplay a grounded, believable character" link="RuleR3"]
  - [textlink="4. Do not metagame; obey the Metashield" link="RuleR4"]
  - [textlink="5. Respect the Safezone; do not interfere with arrivals" link="RuleR5"]
  - [textlink="6. Do not act like an antagonist; no antagonist behavior exists in Prospect Sector" link="RuleR6"]
  - [textlink="7. Do not stall progression or halt the round" link="RuleR7"]
  - [textlink="8. Do not form antagonist groups or hostile factions" link="RuleR8"]
  - [textlink="9. Do not cause excessive death, damage, or destruction" link="RuleR9"]
  - [textlink="10. Respect command and department leadership" link="RuleR10"]
  - [textlink="11. Follow reasonable escalation when resolving conflict" link="RuleR11"]
  - [textlink="12. Do not abandon your role; change roles in-character if necessary" link="RuleR12"]
  - [textlink="13. Stick to the responsibilities of your chosen job" link="RuleR13"]
  - [textlink="14. Command roles must set a positive example" link="RuleR14"]
  - [textlink="15. There is no formal Space Law; resolve issues through RP and leadership" link="RuleR15"]

</Document>

