<Document>
  # Roleplay Rule 14 – Command Must Set an Example

  Prospect Sector has **no security department** and **no antagonist roles**, but **Command** (Station Lead, HoP, QM, department heads) still carry higher expectations than normal crew.

  Command roles:
  - Are **not beginner roles** — you are expected to understand your job and basic game systems.
  - Must maintain a **professional, cooperative tone** that encourages good RP.
  - Should **guide, coordinate, and support** the crew, not control them or act abusively.
  - Must avoid actions that harm station progression, morale, or structure.
  - Should use their authority responsibly and transparently.

  Command has a major impact on how the round develops.
  When command behaves well, the crew usually follows. When command behaves poorly, chaos follows.

  ## Examples

  ### Acceptable:
  - A Station Lead admits a mistake over comms in a lighthearted way.
  - The HoP organizes departments, assists with job changes, and supports station direction.
  - The QM coordinates cargo priorities and loot sorting with clear communication.
  - Command votes to replace a Station Lead who is genuinely harming station progress.
  - A department head temporarily assigns access to allow a project to continue smoothly.
  - Command hosts small RP events (crew meetings, announcements, ceremonies) that do not disrupt station progression.

  ### Prohibited:
  - Command abusing authority to harass, grief, or punish crew without cause.
  - Making memey, trollish, or disruptive announcements that degrade RP quality.
  - Granting high access (engineering, atmos, cargo control, command areas) without a clear IC reason.
  - Demoting or promoting crew based on personal grudges or favoritism.
  - Command taking rare or high-value items for personal use without justification.
  - Command abandoning leadership responsibilities to run off and do unrelated personal projects.
  - Using authority to bypass rules, hinder progression, or excuse harmful behavior.

</Document>
