<Document>
  # Roleplay Rule 5 – Respect the Safezone (Arrivals & Cryo)

  The arrivals shuttle, its docking area, cryo bays, and the immediate surroundings form the **Safezone**.
  This area exists so players can spawn, load in, take a short AFK, sort themselves out, and join the round without being put in danger.

  Because Prospect Sector is a **cooperative, progression-focused game with no antagonist roles**, any hostile or disruptive behavior in the Safezone is strictly prohibited.

  The Safezone must always remain:
  - Safe to spawn in
  - Safe to pause in briefly
  - Free of hazards, traps, or environmental sabotage
  - Free of harassment, baiting, or grief

  The Safezone **must not be damaged, blocked, sabotaged, or used as a staging point for harmful behavior**, even indirectly.
  You may decorate, organize, and lightly modify the Safezone, as long as it remains fully safe and functional.

  ## Examples

  ### Acceptable:
  - Redecorating or visually customizing the Safezone.
  - Expanding or remodeling the area **without** introducing hazards.
  - Placing information boards, job guides, or wayfinding signs.
  - Setting up a small **non-intrusive** checkpoint or welcome desk.
  - Building light-quality-of-life improvements (charging station, disposals, benches).
  - Temporarily moving items as long as the Safezone remains safe and accessible.

  ### Prohibited:
  - Making the Safezone uninhabitable (fires, no air, leaks, broken floors).
  - Damaging the arrivals shuttle or cryo bays.
  - Placing traps, harmful machines, or environmental hazards.
  - Blocking exits or sealing players inside the shuttle.
  - Killing, attacking, or harassing players in or immediately after leaving the Safezone.
  - Removing firelocks, alarms, or atmos safety devices.
  - Electrifying doors, sabotaging vents, or altering atmos pipelines connected to the Safezone.
  - Using construction tools to wall off or isolate arriving players.
  - Dragging hostile mobs, explosives, or environmental dangers into the area.

  ## Special Note
  Prospect Sector has **no antagonist roles**.
  Therefore, there are **no exemptions** that allow you to damage or endanger the Safezone.

  The Safezone is always protected, regardless of round, job, or situation.

</Document>
