<Document>
  # Roleplay Rule 7 – Do Not Stall Progression

  Prospect Sector rounds are designed around **cooperative progression**, where the station is rebuilt, expeditions are completed, and the crew pushes toward higher difficulty tiers.
  A round is expected to move forward at a steady pace. Players should **not deliberately slow, block, or sabotage the natural progression of the round**.

  Actions that intentionally delay upgrades, halt expeditions, obstruct station repairs, or prevent players from progressing toward round completion are considered **round stalling**.

  Because Prospect Sector does not use a traditional evacuation shuttle end condition, round stalling revolves around **progression-based milestones**, not shuttle calls.

  ## What counts as stalling?
  Round stalling includes any behavior that:
  - Stops or severely delays the crew’s ability to advance expedition difficulty.
  - Blocks access to required station systems needed for progression.
  - Intentionally prevents departments from functioning (engineering, cargo, science, etc.).
  - Hoards critical materials, gear, or tools solely to stop others from progressing.
  - Refuses to allow the round to progress when the **majority of active players** want to continue forward.
  - Undermines or halts the natural flow of station development.

  ## What does *not* count as stalling?
  - Taking a reasonable amount of time to prepare the station.
  - Coordinating as a group to push higher difficulty expeditions.
  - Wanting a long, stable round **as long as progression is still happening**.
  - Slowdowns caused by legitimate in-game issues (repairs, low materials, recovering from disasters).
  - A department being busy or understaffed.

  ## Examples

  ### Acceptable:
  - The crew decides to play a longer shift and continue expanding the station, and everyone continues to contribute.
  - Engineering pauses expeditions temporarily to repair major damage after an asteroid event.
  - Cargo delays an expedition launch for a few minutes while sorting returned loot.
  - Command asks for time to build key departments before pushing higher expedition tiers.
  - A player takes a short break or works at a slower pace while still contributing overall.

  ### Prohibited:
  - A player hoards all high-tier gear or materials and refuses to let the station progress.
  - A group refuses to run any expeditions despite the rest of the crew wanting to continue progression.
  - Blocking access to the magnet, expedition gate, or critical machinery to stop progress.
  - Destroying or disabling essential systems (power, atmos, cargo storage, magnet) to freeze progression.
  - Intentionally refusing to complete required objectives that stop the round from ending.
  - Deliberately keeping the station in a broken or unusable state to halt gameplay.

  ## Final Note
  Progression is the core of Prospect Sector.
  You are expected to participate in it—or at the very least, **not prevent others from doing so**.

  Admins have final say on what constitutes round stalling based on the situation.
</Document>
