<Document>
  # Roleplay Rule 15 – Dangerous Equipment Must Be Used and Carried Appropriately

  Prospect Sector allows players to use powerful tools, weapons, and dangerous equipment — **but only in the correct context**.
  Expeditions are hazardous, and players will naturally gear up before launching one.
  However, the **station interior** is a cooperative, civilian environment where openly carrying lethal gear harms RP and atmosphere.

  ## Core Principle
  - **Near the Terradrop machine, expedition prep zones, and staging areas:**
  Carrying visible dangerous gear is **expected and acceptable**.

  - **Elsewhere on the station:**
  Dangerous or lethal equipment must be **stored away** (backpack, belt, locker, personal storage).
  Do not walk around the station visibly armed unless there is an active emergency.

  ## Dangerous Equipment Includes:
  - Expedition-tier weapons (ranged or melee)
  - High-risk tools or devices
  - Heavy engineering equipment that can cause major damage
  - Any gear designed mainly for combat or hazard neutralization

  Normal work tools appropriate to your department **are not restricted**.

  ## Expectations for Command and Senior Roles
  Command and department heads must:
  - Model proper equipment etiquette
  - Encourage safe storage of dangerous gear
  - Prevent the station from becoming a “military base” environment
  - De-escalate improper open-carry situations through RP

  They may authorize visible weapons **only during active emergencies** (fauna breach, reactor failure, hostile event).

  ## Examples

  ### Acceptable:
  - Carrying a visible weapon while waiting at the Terradrop for an upcoming expedition.
  - Wearing expedition armor during prep, testing gear, or loading supplies.
  - Temporarily drawing a weapon inside the station to respond to an immediate threat.
  - Storing weapons in personal storage before leaving the expedition zone.

  ### Prohibited:
  - Wandering around the bar, medbay, cargo, or hallways visibly armed without an emergency.
  - Keeping expedition weapons equipped while performing non-expedition duties.
  - Displaying dangerous devices or weapons in civilian areas for intimidation or spectacle.
  - Using “expedition roleplay” as an excuse to openly carry weapons everywhere.

  ## Roles expected to follow this closely:
  - Command roles (Station Lead, HoP, QM)
  - Department heads
  - Regular crew performing station-side duties
  - Expedition members when they are **not** at the expedition zone

  ## Roles with situational flexibility:
  - Expedition classes (Miner, Salvager, Explorer) **while near Terradrop**
  - Engineering or science roles transporting hazardous gear necessary for repairs/testing
  - Anyone during an admin-confirmed emergency event

  ## Final Note
  Expeditions are dangerous; the station is not.
  Bring your best gear **to the frontier**, not the cafeteria.
  Store dangerous equipment when moving away from the Terradrop zone to maintain RP quality and station safety.

</Document>
