<Document>
  # Roleplay Rule 8 – No Antagonist Teams Exist; Do Not Create Them

  Prospect Sector has **no antagonist roles** and therefore no antagonist teams.
  There are no traitors, operatives, cults, revolutions, zombies, or carp factions controlled by players.

  Because of this, **no player may create or act as part of an antagonist group**, whether formally or informally.

  You may not:
  - Form secret teams with the goal of harming the station
  - Create “villain factions” as a roleplay gimmick
  - Invent your own antagonist objectives
  - Coordinate sabotage, uprisings, or destructive plots
  - Roleplay as Syndicate-aligned, revolutionary, cultist, zombie, or similar groups
  - Encourage others to disrupt the round as part of a shared RP narrative

  All roles in Prospect Sector are cooperative roles.
  No one is permitted to unite into a player-made antagonist force.

  ## Examples

  ### Acceptable:
  - Forming a harmless RP club (gardening club, explorers' guild, bar game night).
  - Cooperating as a group to run expeditions or repair the station.
  - Having disagreements or rivalries as long as they remain non-destructive.
  - A character changing personal goals through RP (career change, personality shift).

  ### Prohibited:
  - Forming a “revolutionary group” to overthrow command.
  - Creating a “cult” with goals tied to sabotage or harm.
  - Coordinating as a team to disrupt engineering, power, atmos, cargo, or expeditions.
  - Acting like a Syndicate cell or inventing your own antagonistic faction.
  - Grouping together to attack or grief crew members.
  - Working to make the station uninhabitable as part of a player-made storyline.
  - Encouraging others to perform sabotage as part of "team RP."
  - Attempting to mimic upstream antagonist factions (ops, heretics, zombies, changelings, cults, etc.).

  ## Final Note
  Prospect Sector is built entirely around **cooperative progression**.
  No player or group may assume, create, or simulate an antagonist role.
  Admins will treat any such behavior as intentional disruption.

</Document>
