<Document>
  # Roleplay Rule 12 – Do Not Abandon Your Role

  When you join a round in Prospect Sector, you are expected to **play the role you selected** and contribute to station progression or expeditions in a reasonable way.

  Abandoning your role includes:
  - Ignoring essential responsibilities of your job
  - Leaving the round without attempting to cryo
  - Wandering off to do unrelated projects while your department is falling apart
  - Taking a role you never intended to play

  This rule is enforced **more strictly for command and critical station roles**, and less strictly for flexible or low-impact roles.

  If you must leave early:
  - Cryo if possible
  - Notify command or your department
  - If you must leave immediately, do so—real life always comes first.
  Patterns of early quitting may result in role bans, but isolated incidents will not.

  ## Examples

  ### Acceptable:
  - As an engineer, building small side projects when the station has stable power and no urgent tasks.
  - As command, taking part in harmless RP or learning another job when the station is stable.
  - As a passenger, working on personal builds with materials provided by other departments.
  - Taking short breaks from your job when you’re not needed urgently.
  - Doing the basic minimum for your job if you are inexperienced or overwhelmed.
  - Trying your best at your job but failing due to inexperience or mistakes.

  ### Prohibited:
  - As an engineer, doing personal projects while the station has no power or major issues.
  - As command, leaving the station unattended to join expeditions when leadership is needed.
  - As atmos, disappearing to build side projects while atmospherics is broken.
  - Ignoring your entire job all round while urgent work needs doing.
  - Leaving, ghosting, or suiciding at round start for personal preference (map, players, etc.).
  - Taking a job just to immediately quit it and do something unrelated.
  - Abandoning your role to chase ghost roles or other unrelated gameplay.

</Document>
