<Document>
  # Roleplay Rule 6 – Do Not Create Chaos or Play as a Hidden Antagonist

  Prospect Sector has **no antagonist roles**.
  All players are expected to contribute positively to station development, expedition progress, and cooperative gameplay.

  Because there are no traitors, nukies, revolutionaries, cults, or similar mechanics, **acting like an antagonist is always against the rules**.

  “Acting like an antagonist” includes:
  - Creating chaos for its own sake
  - Intentionally disrupting station systems
  - Becoming a major problem, obstruction, or danger to the round
  - Undermining other players’ ability to play
  - Sabotaging the station or expeditions
  - Hoarding critical items to stop progression

  Players should either have **no major impact** or a **positive impact** on the round.
  You are not allowed to create a hostile subplot “for fun,” even with RP justification.

  ## Examples

  These examples assume normal gameplay with no special admin events.

  ### Acceptable:
  - Minor pranks such as swapping someone’s shoes for clown shoes.
  - Lighthearted antics that do not impact station progression or safety.
  - Playing a quirky or eccentric character **as long as they remain cooperative**.
  - Rearranging furniture or decor in a way that does not hinder gameplay.
  - Stealing small, non-essential items (a snack, a mug, a pen) as part of harmless RP.

  ### Prohibited:
  - Starting or roleplaying a cult, revolution, rebellion, or mutiny.
  - Deliberately sabotaging engineering, atmos, cargo, science, or expedition systems.
  - Breaking lights, airlocks, or infrastructure across the station.
  - Causing atmosphere leaks or spacing parts of the station.
  - Disrupting station power or disabling generators/smes intentionally.
  - Griefing construction, stealing essential tools, or blocking progress-critical rooms.
  - Distributing high-level access without purpose.
  - Hoarding rare expedition items, materials, or gear to stop others from using them.
  - Removing or hiding crucial equipment needed for progression (magnet parts, materials, machinery, etc.).
  - Attacking crew members without RP justification or escalation.
  - Intentionally derailing an entire department’s ability to function.

  ## Final Note
  Prospect Sector is a **cooperative progression game**, not a PvP deception game.
  You must not create your own antagonist storyline, and you must not behave like a saboteur, villain, or disruptive force.

  Admins have final determination on whether behavior constitutes antagonist-like conduct.
</Document>
